Horace Freeland Judson Collection 1968-1978 Mss.B.J92
American Philosophical Society
Horace Freeland Judson Collection
1968-1978
Mss.B.J92
American Philosophical Society
1.0 Linear feet
Between 1968 and 1978, the historian of science Horace Freeland Judson conducted extensive oral history interviews with biochemists and molecular biologists relating to the development of their field. The correspondence, transcripts of interviews, and taped interviews that comprise the Judson collection formed the research material used by Judson in his book, The Eighth Day of Creation (New York, 1979). Permission to quote must be obtained from Dr. Judson and access to some files is restricted.
1 lin. foot, 52 audiorecordings
Judson, Horace Freeland, 1931-
Biographical/Historical note
After a varied career as graduate student, researcher for the American O.M.G. in Berlin, editor, advertising copywriter, and journalist, Judson found his metier as a chronicler and historian of science. His masterpiece, The Eighth Day of Creation, established him in 1979 as peerless in the use of taped interviews, usually repeated and revised several times, as a basis of probing the actual genesis of discovery and the history of ideas in modern science.
The Horace Judson Papers (1968-1978) contain correspondence and transcripts of interviews with molecular biologists concerning the development of their field. Judson used this research as the basis for a series of articles published as "Annals of Science: DNA" in The New Yorker issues of November 27, December 4, and December 11, 1978, and later compiled them in book-length form as The Eighth Day of Creation: Makers of the Revolution in Biology (New York: Simon & Schuster, 1979).
Many, but not all of Judson's interviews are transcribed in full or entirely verbatim. In some cases, however, the transcripts are sketchy, and might more properly be called notes on a conversation. In case of doubt, the recordings alone (Rec. 113A) are the actual record, and reference should be made to them. It should be stressed that these transcripts and notes were made by Judson and may ignore background discussions that Judson had no need to refer to later, but that others may find of value.
Scope and Contents note
The Judson Papers are comprised of 52 tape recorded oral history interviews and 1 linear foot of transcripts, 1968-1978, arranged alphabetically by the name of the interviewee. The collection forms a major resource for study of the early history of molecular biology and the development of nucleic acid.
Conditions Governing Access note
The files containing material regarding Matthew Meselson, Maurice Wilkinson, and women at King's College are closed indefinitely to researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Horace Judson Papers were donated by Horace Judson in December 1978 (accession number 1979-70ms).
Existence and Location of Copies note
The collection has been microfilmed in its entirety (Film 1402). The microfilm is arranged in a main alphabetical sequence, which is followed by interviews with scientists at the Cavendish Laboratory (Bragg, Kendrew, Barnett, Blow, Huxley, Phillips, and Klug), with scientists and others associated with the Pasteur Institute Laboratory (Jacob, Monod, Gros, Lwoff, Ephrussi, Cohen, Wollman, Perrin, Noufflard, Ullman, Jungelson, and members of Monod's family), with Max Perutz, and finally, by interviews with Brenner and Crick.
Separated Materials note
The audiotapes have been removed for storage to the Audiovisal Collections (Rec. 113a).
Other Finding Aids note
The Judson Collection is also described in Bentley Glass, Guide to the Genetics Collections of the American Philosophical Society (Philadelphia: APS, 1988).
Genetics note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Brenner, Sydney Transcripts (68 pages) 1968-1978
Chargaff, Erwin Transcripts (4 pages) 1972, 1976
Crick, Francis H. C. Transcripts (3 folders) 1968-1978
Delbruck, Max Transcripts (14 pages) 1971-1978
Ephrussi, Boris Transcripts (17 pages) 1975-1976
Gilbert, Walter M. Transcripts (24 pages) 1971-1973
Luria, Salvador Edward Transcripts (19 pages) 1971-1973
McClintock, Barbara Transcripts (6 pages) 1973-1978
Medvedev, Zhores A. Transcripts (9 pages) 1976
Nirenberg, Marshall Transcripts (16 pages) 1971-1977
Pauling, Linus Transcripts (20 pages) 1971-1975
Stent, Gunther S. Transcripts (31 pages) 1976-1977
Watson, James D. Transcripts (56 pages) 1970-1978
Ames, Bruce; Audureau, Alice; Baltimore, David; Barnett, Leslie; Beckett, Samuel; Benzer, Seymour; Berg, Paul, 1926-; Blow, David; Bodmer, Walter; Bragg, William Lawrence, Sir, 1890-1971; Brenner, Sydney; Brown, Angela Martin; Cairns, John; Cambridge University; Caspersson, Torbjörn, (Torbjörn Oskar), 1910-1997; Cavendish Laboratory (Cambridge, England); Chargaff, Erwin; Cohen, Georges; Cohn, Melvin; Cowan, Pauline; Crick, Francis, 1916-2004; Crick, Francis--with Maddox, John; Crick, Francis--with Olby, Robert; Crick, Odile; Davern, Cedric; Delbrück, Max; Donohue, Jerry; Dubos, René; Dulbecco, Renato, 1914-; Dunitz, Jack D.; Engelhardt, Vladimir Alexandrovich; Ephrussi, Boris, 1901-1979; Fell, Dame Honor; Fourcade, Bertrand; Fraenkel-Conrat, Heinz; Fraser, Mary J.; Furberg, Sven; Garen, Alan; Gilbert, Walter; Gosling, Ray; Griffiths, Wendell--with Olby, Robert; Gros, François; Grunberg-Manago, Marianne, 1921-; Guidotti, Guido; Guillemin, Roger; Gurdon, John; Harrison, Pauline Cowan; Haurowitz, Felix; Hayes, William; Heppel, Leon; Hershey, A. D., (Alfred Day), 1908-; Hoagland, Mahlon; Hodgkin, Dorothy Crowfoot; Hogness, David; Holley, Robert W.; Horecker, Bernard; Hotchkiss, Rollin; Hubel, David; Hussain, Farooq; Huxley, Hugh; Ingram, Vernon; Institut Pasteur (Paris, France); Jackson, Sylvia Fitton; Jacob, François, 1920-; Jungelson, Eugene; Kalckar, Herman M., (Herman Moritz), 1908-1991; Kendrew, John; Keynes, Richard D.; Kierkegaard quotation; Klug, Aaron; Kornberg, Roger; Lederberg, Joshua; Lennox, E. S., (Edwin Samuel), 1920-; Lerman, Leonard; Lewis, Herman; Lipmann, Fritz; Lipscomb, William; Luria, S. E., (Salvador Edward), 1912-1991; Luzzati, Vittorio; Lwoff, André, 1902-; M'Ewen, Marjorie; Maaløe, Ole; Maas, Werner; Maddox, John; Markham, Roy; Matthaei, Heinrich; McClintock, Barbara, 1902-1992; Medawar, Peter; Medvedev, Zhores A., 1925-; Mertz, Janet; Meselson, Matthew; Miller, Stanley; Mitchison, Avrian; Monod, Jacques; Monod, Olivier; Monod, Phillipe; Nirenberg, Marshall; North, Margaret Pratt; Noufflard, Geneviève; Ochoa, Severo; Olby, Robert; Orgel, Leslie; Pardee, Arthur; Pauling, Linus, 1901-1994; Pauling, Peter; Perrin, David; Perutz, Max; Phillips, David; Pollack, Robert; Potter, Lincoln; Ptashne, Mark; Rich, Alexander; Ruderman, Warren; Sanger, Frederick; Sayre, Anne; Schachman, Howard; Schmidt, Benno; Shils, E.A.; Singer, Maxine; Smith, John; Spear, Walter Eric; Stent, Gunther; Stoker, Michael; Stokes, Alexander; Swift, Hewson; Szent-Gyorgi, Andrew Gabriel; Temins, Howard; Terheggen, Heinz Georg; Thomas, Charles; Tissières, Alfred; Travers, Andrew; Ullman, Agnès; Watson, James D.; Weil, Adrienne; Wilkins, Maurice; Wollman, Élie; Wyatt, Gerard; Yanofsky, Charles; Zamecnik, Paul; DNA--History; Molecular biology--History; Oral histories
- Transcripts of oral history interviews, 1968-1978; 2 boxes
  - Ames, Bruce, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    May 7, 1978, by telephone to his house in Berkeley
    Aug. 10, 1978, Department of Biochemistry, University of California, Berkeley
  - Audureau, Alice, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Sept. 22, 1976, by telephone to her house in La Baule, France
  - Baltimore, David, 1971; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Feb. 12, [1971], Massachusetts Institute of Technology
  - Barnett, Leslie, 1971; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Jan. 1971, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Beckett, Samuel, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    May 18, 1976, Royal Court Theatre and adjoining pub, London
  - Benzer, Seymour, 1971, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Feb. 25, 1971, California Institute of Technology
    Apr. 30, 1978, by telephone
    May 1, 1978, by telephone
  - Berg, Paul, 1974, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Sept. 6, 1974, by the Cam, Cambridge
    Sept. 18, 1976, Peterhouse, Cambridge
  - Blow, David, 1971; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Jan. 1971, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Bodmer, Walter, 1975; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Mar. 10, 1975, Department of Genetics, Oxford
  - Bragg, Lawrence, 1971; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Jan. 28, 1971, his apartment, The Boltons, London
    n.d., with Robert Olby
  - Brenner, Sydney, 1968-1978; 68 pages (Box 1)
    -See also Crick, Francis, Sept. 1970, Nov. 19, 1975
    [May 8], 1968, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    May 11-14, 1968, letters to Time Science from Judson
    Jan. 26, 1971, King's College, Cambridge
    Jun. 8, 1972, talk, Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton
    Mar. 13, 1975, King's College, Cambridge
    Feb. 7, 1976, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Feb. 28, 1976, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Mar. 1977, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    May 14, 1977, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Mar. 21, 1978, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Drosophila genetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Morgan, Thomas Hunt; Philosophy of science; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Brown, Angela Martin, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    -See also Women at King's College
    2 Sept. 1976, King's College, London
  - Cairns, John, 1974; 1 folder (Box 1)
    [Apr. 1974], Imperial Cancer Research Fund Laboratory, Mill Hill, London
  - Caspersson, Torbjörn, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    22 Dec. 1976, letter to Judson
  - Chargaff, Erwin, 1972, 1976; 4 pages (Box 1)
    15 Feb. [1972], College of Physicians and Surgeons, Columbia University
    3 Sept. 1976, letter from Judson
    25 Sept. 1976, letter to Judson
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Crick, Francis H. C.; Cytogenetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Philosophy of science; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Watson, James D.
  - Cohen, Georges, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    13 Nov. 1976, Institut Pasteur, Paris
  - Cohn, Melvin, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    [Mar.] 1971, cafeteria breakfast, New York City
    13 Jun. 1977, letter to Judson
  - Cowan, Pauline (Box 1)
    -See Harrison, Pauline Cowan
  - Crick, Francis, 1970-1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Sept. 1970, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    1 Sept. 1971, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    22 Sept. 1971, letter to Judson
    3 Jul. 1975, Middlesex Hospital, London
    10 Sept. 1975, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    19-20 Nov. 1975, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    28 Jun. 1977, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
    12 Jul. 1977, letter to Judson
    21 Mar. 1978, letter to Judson
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Chargaff, Erwin; Cytogenetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Pauling, Linus; Philosophy of science; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Watson, James D.
  - Crick, Francis--with Maddox, John, 1974; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Mar. 1974
  - Crick, Francis--with Olby, Robert, 1968; 1 folder (Box 1)
    8 Mar. 1968
  - Crick, Odile, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    10 Jul. 1976, Swaffham Bulbeck
    24 Aug. 1976, the Cricks' house, Portugal Place, Cambridge
  - Davern, Cedric, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    31 May 1978, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
  - Delbrück, Max, 1971-1978; 14 pages (Box 1)
    -See also Kierkegaard quotation
    25 Feb. 1971, his office at the California Institute of Technology
    9? Jul. 1972, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
    26 Jun. 1978, letter to Judson
    Bacterial genetics; Bohr, Niels; Crick, Francis H. C.; Cytogenetics; Gamow, George; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Philosophy of science; Protozoan genetics; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Watson, James D.
  - Donohue, Jerry, 1974, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Summer 1974, University of Pennsylvania
    Feb.-Mar. 1976, letters to and from Judson
  - Dubos, René, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    24 Apr. 1978, by telephone to Rockefeller University
  - Dulbecco, Renato, 1971, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    23 Feb. [1971], Salk Institute
    19 Mar. 1976, Imperial Cancer Research Fund Laboratory, Lincoln's Inn Fields, London
  - Dunitz, Jack D., 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    17 Mar. 1976, letter from Judson
    22 Mar. 1976, letter to Judson
  - Engelhardt, Vladimir Alexandrovich, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    16 Feb. 1977, Fellows' Room of the Royal Society, London
  - Ephrussi, Boris, 1975-1976; 17 pages (Box 1)
    5 Dec. 1975, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, Gif-sur-Yvette
    13 Nov. 1976, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, Gif-sur-Yvette
    Beadle, George Wells; Bridges, Calvin B.; Chargaff, Erwin; Delbruck, Max; Drosophila genetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Monod, Jacques; Morgan, Thomas Hunt; Mouse genetics; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Schultz, Jack; Sturtevant, Alfred Henry; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Watson, James D.; World War II -- France
  - Fell, Dame Honor, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    28 Jan. 1977, Addenbrooks Hospital, Cambridge
  - Fourcade, Bertrand, 1971; 1 folder (Box 1)
    [Apr.] 1971, Travellers' Club, Paris
  - Fraenkel-Conrat, Heinz, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    10 Aug. 1978, Virus Laboratory, University of California, Berkeley
  - Fraser, Mary J. (Box 1)
    -See Women at King's College
  - Furberg, Sven--with Olby, Robert, n.d.; 1 folder (Box 1)
    n.d.
  - Garen, Alan, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    23 Jul. 1977, Algonquin Hotel lobby, New York City
  - Gilbert, Walter, 1971, 1973; 24 pages (Box 1)
    13 Feb. 1971, Biological Laboratories, Harvard University
    14 Feb. 1971, his home, Upland Road, Cambridge, Massachusettts
    Oct. 1973, Biological Laboratories, Harvard University
    Bacterial genetics; Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Cytogenetics; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Research support; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Watson, James D.
  - Gosling, Ray, 1975; 1 folder (Box 1)
    21 Jul. 1975, Guy's Hospital, London
  - Griffiths, Wendell--with Olby, Robert, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Gros, François, 1971, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    12 Oct. 1971, Institut de la Biologie Moleculaire, University of Paris
    15 Nov. 1976, Institut Pasteur, Paris
  - Grunberg-Manago, Marianne, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    14 Sept. 1976, letter to Judson
    16 Nov. 1976, Institut Pasteur, Paris
  - Guidotti, Guido, 1973; 1 folder (Box 1)
    11 Oct. 1973, Biological Laboratories, Harvard University
  - Guillemin, Roger, 1971; 1 folder (Box 1)
    22 Feb. [1971], Salk Institute
  - Gurdon, John, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    22 Jan. 1976, seminar at MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Harrison, Pauline Cowan, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    22 Jan. 1977, by telephone to University of Sheffield, England
  - Haurowitz, Felix, 1972; 1 folder (Box 1)
    4 Feb. 1972, letter to Judson
  - Hayes, William, 19786; 1 folder (Box 1)
    31 Aug. 1976, letter from Judson
    24 Sept. 1976, letter to Judson
    5 Oct. 1976, Royal Society, London
  - Heppel, Leon, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    26 Jul. 1977, by telephone to Cornell University
  - Hershey, Alfred D., 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    27 Aug. 1976, letter from Judson
    8 Sept. 1976, letter to Judson
  - Hoagland, Mahlon, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    9 Aug. 1977, Rockland, Maine
  - Hodgkin, Dorothy Crowfoot, 1971; 1 folder (Box 1)
    [8 Jan. 1971], her laboratory at University of Oxford
  - Hogness, David, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    18 Feb. 1977, Royal Society, London
  - Holley, Robert W., 1971, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    22 Feb. 1971, Salk Institute
    23 Nov. 1977, letter to Judson
  - Horecker, Bernard, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    27 Feb. 1978, his apartment, East 64th Street, New York City
  - Hotchkiss, Rollin, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    12 Jun. 1978, Rockefeller University
    18 Jul. 1978, Rockefeller University
    20 Jul. 1978, by telephone
  - Hubel, David, 1971; 1 folder (Box 1)
    12 Feb. 1971, Harvard Medical School
  - Hussain, Farooq, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    12 Jan. 1976, King's College, London
  - Huxley, Hugh, 1971; 1 folder (Box 1)
    19 Feb. 1971, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Ingram, Vernon, 1971, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    [Mar. 1971], Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    11 Aug. 1977, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
  - Jackson, Sylvia Fitton, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    30 Jun. 1976, Darwin College, Cambridge
  - Jacob, François, 1970-1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Sept. 1970, Institut Pasteur, Paris
    9 Dec. 1970, Institut Pasteur, Paris
    3 Dec. 1975, Institut Pasteur, Paris
    28 May 1977, his apartment, rue Guyamer, Paris
    5 May 1978, Dana Palmer House, Harvard
  - Jungelson, Eugene, 1976, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    17 Nov. 1976, his office, Boulevard St. German, Paris
    27 May 1977, his office, Boulevard St. German, Paris
  - Kalckar, Herman, 1973-1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Sept. 1973, Harvard Medical School
    27 Aug. 1976, from Judson
    13 Sept. 1976, to Judson
  - Kendrew, John, 1971, 1975; 1 folder (Box 1)
    13-14 Jan. 1971, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    11 Nov. 1975, office of Journal of Molecular Biology, Cambridge
  - Keynes, Richard D., 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    9 Feb. 1976, Physiology Laboratories & Graduate Student Center, Cambridge
  - Kierkegaard quotation, 1975-1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    -See also Wilkins, Maurice
    1975-1976, letters
  - Klug, Aaron, 1972-1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Aug. 1972(?), MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    6 Jun. 1975, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    27 Jun. 1975, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    Oct. 1975, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    19 Jan. 1976, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Kornberg, Roger, 1974, 1975; 1 folder (Box 1)
    19 Nov. [1974], MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
    12 Sept. 1975, Cosin Court, Peterhouse, Cambridge
  - Lederberg, Joshua, 1977, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    1 Aug. 1977, by telephone to Stanford University
    9 Aug. 1978, Stanford University
  - Lennox, Edwin, 1971, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Feb. 1971, Christ Cella's, New York City
    7 Feb. 1978, MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Lerman, Leonard, 1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    4 Aug. 1977, by telephone to Department of Biological Sciences, SUNY, Albany
  - Lewis, Herman, 1973; 1 folder (Box 1)
    1 Oct. 1973, National Science Foundation
  - Lipmann, Fritz, 1971, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    19 Mar. 1971, Rockefeller University
    7 Jul. 1977, Rockefeller University
    11 Oct. 1978, Rockefeller University
  - Lipscomb, William, 1978; 1 folder (Box 1)
    20 Jun. 1978, Harvard University
  - Luria, Salvador E., 1971, 1973; 19 pages (Box 1)
    17 Mar. 1971, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    [3 Oct. 1973], Lexington, Massachusetts
    [4] Oct. 1973, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    Bacterial genetics; Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Delbruck, Max; Embryology, developmental genetics; Evolution; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Philosophy of science; Population, demography; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Luzzati, Vittorio, 1975, 1976; 1 folder (Box 1)
    2 Dec. 1975, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, Gif-sur-Yvette
    21 Sept. 1976, letter to Judson
  - Lwoff, André, 1975-1977; 1 folder (Box 1)
    13 Jun. 1977, by telephone from Cambridge to Banyuls sur Mer
  - Maaløe, Ole, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Apr. 1, 1977, by telephone from Cambridge to Copenhagen
  - Maas, Werner, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Mar. 1, 1978, by telephone to his office at New York University Medical Center
  - McClintock, Barbara, 1973-1978; 6 pages (Box 2)
    Jun. 1973, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
    Jul. 30, 1978, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
    n.d., her comments
    Biographical and personal data; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Monod, Jacques; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Watson, James D.; Zea (maize) genetics
  - Maddox, John, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Dec. 1970, editorial office of Nature, Little Essex Street, London
  - Markham, Roy, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Sept. 3, 1976, letter from Judson
    Sept. 15, 1976, letter to Judson
  - Matthaei, Heinrich, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Apr. 22, 1976, Max-Planck-Institut für Experimentelle Medizin, Göttingen
  - Medawar, Peter, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Oct. 13, 1975, lecture at Chemistry Building, University of Cambridge
  - Medvedev, Zhores A., 1976; 9 pages (Box 2)
    Feb. 5, 1976, letter from Judson
    Feb. 9, 1976, letter to Judson
    Feb. 16, 1976, National Institute for Medical Research, Mill Hill, London
    Biographical and personal data; Crick, Francis H. C.; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Russian politics and science; Russian politics and science -- Lysenko, Trofim Denisovich; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Watson, James D.
  - Mertz, Janet, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Nov. 25, [1976], MRC Laboratory, Cambridge
  - Meselson, Matthew [closed to researchers], 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    [Mar. 1971], Lexington, Massachusetts
    Oct. [3, 1971], Lexington, Massachusetts
    Aug. 28, 1975, Boston Airport
    1976-1977, letters to and from Judson
    Aug. 8, 1977, his house in Kirkland Place, Cambridge, Massachusetts
    n.d., his comments
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Closed to research
  - M'Ewen, Marjorie, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Miller, Stanley, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Aug. 8, 1978, his office at University of California, San Diego
  - Mitchison, Avrian, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Dec. 30, 1970, London
  - Monod, Jacques, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Dec. [9], 1970, Institut Pasteur, Paris
    Oct. 5, 1971, Institut Pasteur, Paris
    Dec. 1, 1975, his apartment, Avenue de la Bourdonnais, Paris
    Dec. 4, 1975, his apartment, Avenue de la Bourdonnais, Paris
  - Monod, Olivier, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Nov. 13, 1976, his apartment, rue de la Grande Chaumière, Paris
  - Monod, Phillipe, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Nov. 15, 1976, his apartment, rue de la Tombe Issoir, Paris
    [Nov. 16, 1976], by telephone
  - Nature, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Aug. 31, 1976, letter from Judson
    Sept. 1, 1976, letter to Judson
    Sept. 30, 1976, letter from Judson
    Oct. 3, 1976, letter to Judson
  - Nirenberg, Marshall, 1971-1977; 16 pages (Box 2)
    Mar. 11, 1971, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland
    Jul. 25, 1977, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland
    Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Cancer, chemotherapy; History of biology, especially genetics; Molecular genetics; National Institutes of Health; Publication -- The Eighth Day of Creation; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - North, Margaret Pratt, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Jan. 21, 1977, by telephone from Cambridge to Leeds
    Feb. 2, 1977, letter to Judson
  - Noufflard, Geneviève, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Nov. 16, 1976, her apartment, 61 rue de Varennes, Paris
  - Ochoa, Severo, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Apr. 21, 1978, by telephone to his apartment in New York City
    Sept. 14, 1978, New York University Club
  - Orgel, Leslie, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Aug. 8, 1978, Salk Institute
  - Pardee, Arthur, 1978; 1 folder (Box 2)
    Feb. 23, 1978, his house, Brookline, Massachusetts
    Jun. 30, 1978, letter to Judson
    Aug. 4, 1978, letter to Judson
  - Pauling, Linus, 1971-1975; 20 pages (Box 2)
    Mar. 1, 1971, Stanford University